Akash Chaudhary, Master's student @ UC Santa Cruz

131 Walti St, Apt C Santa Cruz, CA, USA 510-203-8170 achaud10@ucsc.edu https://akashchaudharyportfolio.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Psychology-based UX researcher with 5+ years of experience in conducting user research. 3 years of experience working as a Product Manager in industry. Looking to explore work opportunities in UX Research/Product Manager roles. Spearheaded two research teams towards top-tier HCI conference full paper acceptance.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

University of California, Santa Cruz

MS, Computational Media

Advisor - Dr Norman Su 2021 - Present

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

B. Tech, Production and Industrial Engg Advisor - Dr Apurbba Kumar Sharma 2011 - 2015

SKILLS

- Expertise in conducting user research using – diary studies, think aloud testing, design analysis
- Formulating and conducting surveys and interviews
- High/low fidelity prototyping Paper sketches, powerpoints, storyboards, Figma
- Development Python, CSS, HTML, Javascript, P5
- Communications across Operations, Marketing and Tech.
- Time management, leadership, collaboration, and empathy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Researcher University of California, Santa Cruz

September 2021 - Present

Conducts user research. Delivered a full paper conference submission as lead author at ACM Designing Interactive Systems 2022. Collaborated with design interns for conducting user studies on video streaming platforms' UI. Maintained work collaboration among team members. Taught as a teaching assistant for 6 months.

Research Associate Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi January 2018 - July 2021

Published a full research paper on speech improvement at ACM Mobile HCI 2021. Adapted a film school-based teaching methodology into a mobile application.

Collaborated with visual design experts to design user studies. User tested low fidelity prototypes to come up with 8 design requirements. Developed an iOS application and user tested the app for usability scores.

Data Analyst Intern Verisk Innovative Analytics

January 2019 - Sep 2019

Performed accuracy tests on language-based BERT model. Documented weekly reports of fine-tuning parameters in BERT's Q/A model. Achieved a 1.2% enhancement in performance accuracy.

Product Manager Derbii (Cab aggregation startup)

November 2015 - December 2017

Documented user feedback on early stage android and iOS mobile applications. Assessed feedback to discover user pain points. Formulated reports to suggest future research and develop new app features.